Bite the Bullet is a action, western, adventure film directed by Richard Brooks.
At the beginning of the 20th century, a newspaper organizes an
endurance horse race : 700 miles to run in a few days.
9 adventurers are competing, among them a woman, Miss Jones, a Mexican, an Englishman, a
young cow-boy, an old one and two friends, Sam Clayton and Luke Matthews.
All those individualists will learn to respect each other.
Sam Clayton, played by Gene Hackman.
Miss Jones, played by Candice Bergen.
Luke Matthews, played by James Coburn.
Mister, played by Ben Johnson.
Sir Harry Norfolk, played by Ian Bannen.
Carbo, played by Jan-Michael Vincent.
Bite the Bullet is a 1975 American Western film written, produced, and directed by Richard Brooks and starring Gene Hackman, Candice
Bergen, and James Coburn, with Ian Bannen, Jan-Michael Vincent, Ben Johnson and Dabney Coleman in supporting roles.
Brooks called it "my love poem to America.
I love those people and the beauty of our country."
The film explores themes of horse race, horse, endurance, ex prostitute.